<topics>

<top>
<num>412 </num>
<title> airport security </title>
<desc> Description: 
What security measures are in effect or are proposed
to go into effect in airports?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document could identify a specific airport
and describe the security measures already in effect 
or proposed for use at that airport.  Relevant items
could also describe a failure of security that was
cited as a contributing cause of a tragedy which came 
to pass or which was later averted.  Comparisons between
and among airports based on the effectiveness of the
security of each are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>413 </num>
<title> steel production </title>
<desc> Description: 
What are new methods of producing steel?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents will discuss the processes adapted
by entrepreneurs who have organized so-called "minimills"
and are producing steel by methods which differ from
the old blast furnace method of production.  Documents 
that identify the new companies, the problems they have
have encountered, and/or their successes or failures in
the national and international markets are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>427</num>
<title> UV damage, eyes </title>
<desc> Description: 
Find documents that discuss the damage ultraviolet (UV)
light from the sun can do to eyes.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will discuss diseases that result
from exposure of the eyes to UV light, treatments
for the damage, and/or education programs that help
prevent damage.  Documents discussing treatment
methods for cataracts and ocular melanoma are relevant
even when a specific cause is not mentioned.  However,
documents that discuss radiation damage from nuclear
sources or lasers are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>444 </num>
<title> supercritical fluids</title>
<desc> Description: 
What are the potential uses for supercritical fluids
as an environmental protection measure?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document must indicate that the 
fluid involved is achieved by a process of pressurization
producing the supercritical fluid.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>449 </num>
<title> antibiotics ineffectiveness </title>
<desc> Description: 
What has caused the current ineffectiveness of
antibiotics against infections and what is
the prognosis for new drugs?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document must discuss the reasons or 
causes for the ineffectiveness of current antibiotics.
Relevant documents may also include efforts by pharmaceutical
companies and federal government agencies to find new cures, 
updating current testing phases, new drugs being tested,
and the prognosis for the availability of new and effective
antibiotics. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>401 </num>
<title> foreign minorities, Germany </title>
<desc> Description: 
What language and cultural differences impede the integration 
of foreign minorities in Germany?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will focus on the causes of the lack of
integration in a significant way; that is, the mere mention of
immigration difficulties is not relevant.  Documents that discuss
immigration problems unrelated to Germany are also not relevant.  
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>409 </num>
<title> legal, Pan Am, 103 </title>
<desc> Description: 
What legal actions have resulted from the destruction
of Pan Am Flight 103 over Lockerbie, Scotland, on
December 21, 1988?  
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents describing any charges, claims, or fines 
presented to or imposed by any court or tribunal are
relevant, but documents that discuss charges made in
diplomatic jousting are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>404 </num>
<title> Ireland, peace talks </title>
<desc> Description: 
How often were the peace talks in Ireland delayed
or disrupted as a result of acts of violence?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Any interruptions to the peace process not directly
attributable to acts of violence are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>441 </num>
<title> Lyme disease </title>
<desc> Description: 
How do you prevent and treat Lyme disease?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents that discuss current prevention and
treatment techniques for Lyme disease are
relevant.  Reports of research on new
treatments of the disease are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>417 </num>
<title> creativity </title>
<desc> Description: 
Find ways of measuring creativity.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant items include definitions of creativity,
descriptions of characteristics associated with
creativity, and factors linked to creativity. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>438 </num>
<title> tourism, increase </title>
<desc> Description: 
What countries are experiencing an increase in
tourism?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will name a country that
has experienced an increase in tourism.
The increase must represent the nation as a whole
and tourism in general, not be restricted to only
certain regions of the country or to some specific
type of tourism (e.g., adventure travel).  Documents
discussing only projected increases are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>423 </num>
<title> Milosevic, Mirjana Markovic </title>
<desc> Description: 
Find references to Milosevic's wife, Mirjana Markovic.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Any mention of the Serbian president's wife is
relevant, even if she is not named.  She may be referred to
by her nickname, Mira.  A general mention of his family, 
without specifying his wife, is not relevant. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>407 </num>
<title> poaching, wildlife preserves </title>
<desc> Description: 
What is the impact of poaching on 
the world's various wildlife preserves? 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document must discuss poaching in wildlife
preserves, not in the wild itself.  Also deemed relevant
is evidence of preventive measures being taken by local
authorities.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>429 </num>
<title> Legionnaires' disease </title>
<desc> Description: 
Identify outbreaks of Legionnaires' disease.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document must discuss a specific outbreak
of Legionnaires' disease.  Documents that address prevention of
or cures for the disease without citing a specific case are 
not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>402 </num>
<title> behavioral genetics </title>
<desc> Description: 
What is happening in the field of behavioral genetics,
the study of the relative influence of genetic
and environmental factors on an individual's behavior
or personality?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents describing genetic or environmental factors relating
to understanding and preventing substance abuse and addictions
are relevant.  Documents pertaining to attention deficit disorders
tied in with genetics are also relevant, as are genetic disorders 
affecting hearing or muscles.  The genome project is relevant
when tied in with behavior disorders (i.e., mood disorders,
Alzheimer's disease). 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>416 </num>
<title> Three Gorges Project </title>
<desc> Description: 
What is the status of The Three Gorges Project?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will provide the projected
date of completion of the project, its estimated
total cost, or the estimated electrical output of
the the finished project.  Discussions of the
social, political, or ecological impact of the
project are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>410 </num>
<title> Schengen agreement </title>
<desc> Description: 
Who is involved in the Schengen agreement to eliminate border
controls in Western Europe and what do they hope to accomplish?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents will contain any information about the
actions of signatories of the Schengen agreement such as:
measures to eliminate border controls (removal of traffic
obstacles, lifting of traffic restrictions); implementation
of the information system data bank that contains unified
visa issuance procedures; or strengthening of border controls
at the external borders of the treaty area in exchange for 
free movement at the internal borders.  Discussions of border 
crossovers for business purposes are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>446 </num>
<title> tourists, violence </title>
<desc> Description: 
Where are tourists likely to be subjected to
acts of violence causing bodily harm or death?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document must contain accounts of known 
harm to tourists.  Evidence of single, isolated
incidents are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>433 </num>
<title> Greek, philosophy, stoicism </title>
<desc> Description: 
Is there contemporary interest in the Greek
philosophy of stoicism?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Actual references to the philosophy or philosophers, 
productions of Greek stoic plays, and new "stoic" 
artistic productions are all relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>437 </num>
<title> deregulation, gas, electric </title>
<desc> Description: 
What has been the experience of residential utility
customers following deregulation of gas and electric?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents that discuss privatization of government-
owned utilities alone are not relevant.  Also, not
relevant are documents that discuss the deregulation 
of utilities for commercial customers.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>439 </num>
<title> inventions, scientific discoveries </title>
<desc> Description: 
What new inventions or scientific discoveries have been
made?  
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
The word "new" in the description is defined as occurring
in the 1990s.  Documents that indicate a "recent" 
invention or scientific discovery are considered relevant.
Discoveries made in astronomy or any scientific discoveries
that are not patentable are not relevant.  
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>440 </num>
<title> child labor </title>
<desc> Description: 
What steps are being taken by governments or corporations 
to eliminate abuse of child labor?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document identifies an action taken by either 
a private commercial corporation or governmental organization 
to reduce or eliminate the use of child labor in manufacturing 
operations.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>447 </num>
<title> Stirling engine </title>
<desc> Description: 
What new developments and applications are there
for the Stirling engine?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Any discussion of new developments and applications of the
Stirling engine (also known as the Stirling cycle) are relevant. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>405 </num>
<title> cosmic events </title>
<desc> Description: 
What unexpected or unexplained cosmic events or
celestial phenomena, such as radiation and 
supernova outbursts or new comets, have been detected?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
New theories or new interpretations concerning 
known celestial objects made as a result of new 
technology are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>411 </num>
<title> salvaging, shipwreck, treasure </title>
<desc> Description: 
Find information on shipwreck salvaging: the
recovery or attempted recovery of treasure from
sunken ships.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will provide information on
the actual locating and recovery of treasure; 
on the technology which makes possible the discovery,
location and investigation of wreckages which 
contain or are suspected of containing treasure; or
on the disposition of the recovered treasure. 
</narr>
</top>

</topics>