<topics>

<top>
<num>425 </num>
<title> counterfeiting money </title>
<desc> Description: 
What counterfeiting of money is being done in
modern times?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents must cite actual instances
of counterfeiting.   Anti-counterfeiting measures by
themselves are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>407 </num>
<title> poaching, wildlife preserves </title>
<desc> Description: 
What is the impact of poaching on 
the world's various wildlife preserves? 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document must discuss poaching in wildlife
preserves, not in the wild itself.  Also deemed relevant
is evidence of preventive measures being taken by local
authorities.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>408 </num>
<title> tropical storms </title>
<desc> Description: 
What tropical storms (hurricanes and typhoons) have
caused significant property damage and loss of life?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
The date of the storm, the area affected, and the extent of 
damage/casualties are all of interest.  Documents that describe
the damage caused by a tropical storm as "slight", "limited", or
"small" are not relevant. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>404 </num>
<title> Ireland, peace talks </title>
<desc> Description: 
How often were the peace talks in Ireland delayed
or disrupted as a result of acts of violence?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Any interruptions to the peace process not directly
attributable to acts of violence are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>444 </num>
<title> supercritical fluids</title>
<desc> Description: 
What are the potential uses for supercritical fluids
as an environmental protection measure?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document must indicate that the 
fluid involved is achieved by a process of pressurization
producing the supercritical fluid.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>413 </num>
<title> steel production </title>
<desc> Description: 
What are new methods of producing steel?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents will discuss the processes adapted
by entrepreneurs who have organized so-called "minimills"
and are producing steel by methods which differ from
the old blast furnace method of production.  Documents 
that identify the new companies, the problems they have
have encountered, and/or their successes or failures in
the national and international markets are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>437 </num>
<title> deregulation, gas, electric </title>
<desc> Description: 
What has been the experience of residential utility
customers following deregulation of gas and electric?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents that discuss privatization of government-
owned utilities alone are not relevant.  Also, not
relevant are documents that discuss the deregulation 
of utilities for commercial customers.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>450 </num>
<title> King Hussein, peace </title>
<desc> Description: 
How significant a figure over the years was the late
Jordanian King Hussein in furthering peace in the 
Middle East?  
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document must include mention of Israel;
King Hussein himself as opposed to other Jordanian
officials; discussion of the King's on-going, previous 
or upcoming efforts; and efforts pertinent to the peace 
process, not merely Jordan's relationship with other 
middle-east countries or the U.S. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>434 </num>
<title> Estonia, economy </title>
<desc> Description: 
What is the state of the economy of Estonia?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents that give concrete economic information
such as economic statistics, entering economic unions
and treaties, or monetary performance are relevant,
as are discussions of economic issues such as 
transportation or pollution.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>442 </num>
<title> heroic acts </title>
<desc> Description: 
Find accounts of selfless heroic acts by individuals or 
small groups for the benefit of others or a cause.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Relevant documents will contain a description of specific
acts.  General statements concerning heroic acts are not
relevant. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>403 </num>
<title> osteoporosis </title>
<desc> Description: 
Find information on the effects of the dietary intakes
of potassium, magnesium and fruits and vegetables as
determinants of bone mineral density in elderly men
and women thus preventing osteoporosis (bone decay). 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document may include one or more of the
dietary intakes in the prevention of osteoporosis.
Any discussion of the disturbance of nutrition and
mineral metabolism that results in a decrease in 
bone mass is also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>427</num>
<title> UV damage, eyes </title>
<desc> Description: 
Find documents that discuss the damage ultraviolet (UV)
light from the sun can do to eyes.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will discuss diseases that result
from exposure of the eyes to UV light, treatments
for the damage, and/or education programs that help
prevent damage.  Documents discussing treatment
methods for cataracts and ocular melanoma are relevant
even when a specific cause is not mentioned.  However,
documents that discuss radiation damage from nuclear
sources or lasers are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>402 </num>
<title> behavioral genetics </title>
<desc> Description: 
What is happening in the field of behavioral genetics,
the study of the relative influence of genetic
and environmental factors on an individual's behavior
or personality?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents describing genetic or environmental factors relating
to understanding and preventing substance abuse and addictions
are relevant.  Documents pertaining to attention deficit disorders
tied in with genetics are also relevant, as are genetic disorders 
affecting hearing or muscles.  The genome project is relevant
when tied in with behavior disorders (i.e., mood disorders,
Alzheimer's disease). 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>443 </num>
<title> U.S., investment, Africa </title>
<desc> Description: 
What is the extent of U.S. (government and private)
investment in sub-Saharan Africa?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
All references to U.S. Governmental and private assistance
to sub-Saharan Africa are relevant.  Documents discussing
contributions by reason of U.S. membership in international
aid organizations are also relevant. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>449 </num>
<title> antibiotics ineffectiveness </title>
<desc> Description: 
What has caused the current ineffectiveness of
antibiotics against infections and what is
the prognosis for new drugs?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
To be relevant, a document must discuss the reasons or 
causes for the ineffectiveness of current antibiotics.
Relevant documents may also include efforts by pharmaceutical
companies and federal government agencies to find new cures, 
updating current testing phases, new drugs being tested,
and the prognosis for the availability of new and effective
antibiotics. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>448 </num>
<title> ship losses </title>
<desc> Description: 
Identify instances in which weather was a main or contributing
factor in the loss of a ship at sea.  
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Any ship loss due to weather is relevant, either in international
or coastal waters.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>446 </num>
<title> tourists, violence </title>
<desc> Description: 
Where are tourists likely to be subjected to
acts of violence causing bodily harm or death?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document must contain accounts of known 
harm to tourists.  Evidence of single, isolated
incidents are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>411 </num>
<title> salvaging, shipwreck, treasure </title>
<desc> Description: 
Find information on shipwreck salvaging: the
recovery or attempted recovery of treasure from
sunken ships.
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will provide information on
the actual locating and recovery of treasure; 
on the technology which makes possible the discovery,
location and investigation of wreckages which 
contain or are suspected of containing treasure; or
on the disposition of the recovered treasure. 
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>405 </num>
<title> cosmic events </title>
<desc> Description: 
What unexpected or unexplained cosmic events or
celestial phenomena, such as radiation and 
supernova outbursts or new comets, have been detected?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
New theories or new interpretations concerning 
known celestial objects made as a result of new 
technology are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>412 </num>
<title> airport security </title>
<desc> Description: 
What security measures are in effect or are proposed
to go into effect in airports?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document could identify a specific airport
and describe the security measures already in effect 
or proposed for use at that airport.  Relevant items
could also describe a failure of security that was
cited as a contributing cause of a tragedy which came 
to pass or which was later averted.  Comparisons between
and among airports based on the effectiveness of the
security of each are also relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>406 </num>
<title> Parkinson's disease </title>
<desc> Description: 
What is being done to treat the symptoms of 
Parkinson's disease and keep the patient 
functional as long as possible?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document identifies a drug or treatment 
program utilized in patient care and provides 
an indication of success or failure.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>439 </num>
<title> inventions, scientific discoveries </title>
<desc> Description: 
What new inventions or scientific discoveries have been
made?  
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
The word "new" in the description is defined as occurring
in the 1990s.  Documents that indicate a "recent" 
invention or scientific discovery are considered relevant.
Discoveries made in astronomy or any scientific discoveries
that are not patentable are not relevant.  
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>421 </num>
<title> industrial waste disposal </title>
<desc> Description: 
How is the disposal of industrial waste being accomplished
by industrial management throughout the world? 
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents that discuss the disposal, storage, or management
of industrial waste---both standard and hazardous---are
relevant.  However, documents that discuss disposal or
storage of nuclear or radioactive waste, or the illegal
shipment or dumping of waste to avoid legal disposal
methods are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>416 </num>
<title> Three Gorges Project </title>
<desc> Description: 
What is the status of The Three Gorges Project?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
A relevant document will provide the projected
date of completion of the project, its estimated
total cost, or the estimated electrical output of
the the finished project.  Discussions of the
social, political, or ecological impact of the
project are not relevant.
</narr>
</top>

<top>
<num>418 </num>
<title> quilts, income </title>
<desc> Description: 
In what ways have quilts been used to generate income?
</desc>
<narr> Narrative: 
Documents mentioning quilting books, quilting classes,
quilted objects, and museum exhibits of quilts are all relevant.  
Documents that discuss AIDs quilts are irrelevant, unless 
there is specific mention that the quilts are being used 
for fundraising.
</narr>
</top>

</topics>